I think people just make this jump
though when I give those talks
especially the Recon one they're like oh
recon's gonna find me bugs and that is
not that's where it falls apart right
like Recon doesn't really find you bugs
what Jason yeah like so so I use Recon
and I give all these esoteric methods of
Recon and I make a whole talk about
Recon to find more apps to hack
[Music]
thank you
okay so Jason let me let me start this
off with this okay
I think you're one of the the first role
models that I had in the bug Bounty
world to vertically honest man like I
remember I don't know why this memory is
so like strong for me but I remember
sitting on the floor in my room when I
just moved and I was like dude
I I think I got to do this book Bounty
thing and just you know searching and
finding your video your um I think it
was one of your level up videos with bug
crowd and uh you know the bug bug bounty
hunting methodology
um you know videos and I just sat there
and I just watched it like four times on
repeat and I was like you know what I'm
gonna have Mastery of every single one
of these things so I don't know it's
just it's just one of the one of my
first memories that I had with it so I'm
really I'm really grateful to have you
on the show man that means a lot to me
it really does thank you
I mean you were definitely one of the
first like major resources that I looked
up in bug Benny for like how to start
hacking and like what to even like do
when it comes to like hacking and how to
find bugs and all that kind of stuff
that's that's so awesome you know when
you uh when you get older in the game uh
you know younger guys like yourself who
come along who are just like so much
better than me honestly saying that you
they took inspiration from you feels it
feels great so I'm glad I'm doing
something positive so yeah yeah for sure
man and and yeah absolutely inspiration
and and so I I had a couple things here
I I want to give you an opportunity to
do your own introduction
um but I also wanted to give a little
introduction myself first time ever
doing an introduction on a podcast like
this so Jason Haddix if you guys haven't
heard of them you're doing something
wrong
um OG hacker really really shares some
amazing content
um for for bug bounty hunting
methodology in particular
um I guess when I think of you Jason a
couple things pop to pop into my mind
first of all you know you have street
cred in the industry right like you you
were number one hacker on bug crowd for
a while like you're in the weeds doing
the hacking in even to this day still
doing the hacking but now you've you've
pivoted a little bit into your CSO now
right yeah correct yeah
so this is kind of where you know this
is kind of where I kind of see I see two
paths in the future for Justin right I
can go the I can go sort of the the
Franz Rosen path the the entrepreneur
like he's out there he has like three
companies or something like that or I
can go the Jason haddocks of like all
right I want to be c-suite I want to be
you know helping manage the cyber
security program from a top level so
you've pulled that off and the other
things that just kind of come to my head
we've already talked about what kind of
a great educator you are but also
another another role model piece for me
is just a part of your online Persona
and something that you are very public
about is you know being a great dad and
uh I I think it's really refreshing to
see that sort of prioritization in
industry and even when we were
scheduling this podcast you were like
hey you know yeah I can come on but
actually I've got to spend some time
with my family
um and I've got that blocked off from
here to here and I was just like man
this guy's [__] so yeah we couldn't like
him anymore yes
he's a family man too
thank you thanks so much yeah with that
you know why don't you give us a little
bit of an uh a self intro yourself and
uh yeah absolutely um yeah so uh like I
said Jason Haddix I've um I've been in
the offensive security scene I would say
for probably about 15 years
um so uh really I got started you know
shortly after the Loft era where we we
started to see more consultancies doing
penetration testing as kind of the main
thing and dash scanners were just
starting to come out and stuff like that
and so
um you know really I I was in uh College
I did a dark net diarrhea story of kind
of like my story but
um you know I was in college and I was
mostly on the Underground scene back
when Shadow crew was a thing it was a
big underline underground Forum before
the dark web was really a dark web and
um
yeah I was learning hacking there I was
originally just making fake credit cards
uh or not fake credit cards sorry fake
IDs
um Big Ideas yeah
no no no sorry uh fake IDs sorry free
coffee but um yeah I was making I was
making fake IDs and uh just for me and
my friends and then part of that Forum
ecosystem is like the people who use the
fake IDs for the karting and the other
part of that Forum you know underground
kind of lifestyles of people who provide
the dumps which is the credit card
numbers and those are the hackers really
and so yeah
um you know I was starting to get some
exposure to hacking there and then I
took an elective at my college which was
a junior college and it was called
ethical hacking and network defense it
was just one class wow yeah and it was
old already by the time it was out it
was like super old they were talking
about like back orifice and stuff like
that but I was talking to my teacher and
he's like yeah you can make money you
know being a professional like hacker
and I was like that is exactly what I
want to do like that sounds amazing
um and so I just kind of threw myself
into it from like my early 20s
um into everything so back then it was a
lot of net pen service exploitation with
like generic you know you know buffer
overflows Webb was really starting to
take off like SQL injection and
rainforest puppy were
um you know we're just starting to take
off yes yeah yeah exactly yeah uh anyway
so I did that I um
I went on to a small consultancy uh and
then eventually after that I landed at
HP working with a really great team at
HP we built a small little startup
inside of HP called Shadow Labs which
was a testing team and it was one of the
best experiences in my life worked with
some great people and we did a lot of
cutting edge mobile research back when
before iOS pivoted to Swift We were you
know back on The Objective C train and
tons of mobile research there I built a
binary analysis tool there did a whole
bunch of web penetration testing and
then left because bug crowd was around
and so I knew Casey from the industry
and he was like uh he was like yo I'm
starting this thing I'm really only
doing it via email right now there was
no platform literally they just emailed
you a program and a scope and they were
like and I think they used back then
they used like SurveyMonkey or something
to run the whole thing it was crazy and
so he's like I'm literally just gonna
give me give me some context on this
what year was this
so you guys asked me to bring some uh
you asked me to bring some uh bugs let
me just go back to my submission
timeline yeah for sure do that and I
just I'm interested because you said you
knew Casey from the industry yeah and
you know if you're it's really cool that
you were like one of these one of these
you know first people interacting with
bug crowd um as they were starting to I
mean it really seems like they were
almost in like minimum viable product
phase back oh yeah yeah for sure they
were I mean they uh it was J cran and
Casey and like I think five other people
they just moved into an office in San
Francisco all crammed in like a garage
office somewhere
um and uh yeah and so they were managing
everything via SurveyMonkey so your your
bug submissions would be to like a
SurveyMonkey URL and then they'd be
handled like support tickets for like
you know a support place
um and then they would just send you an
email and they're like and this is back
in the day of time boxed um so like you
know it would be like 48 hours this
program is going to be open
um 48 Hours program's gonna be open
here's the scope uh and uh first come
first serve until so much money was
exhausted and that was the old format
um of most of the bounties and so like
we still see that a little bit it's a
little yeah I think they mostly do that
when they're onboarding you know new
programs and stuff like that nowadays
too yeah yeah the the exhausting the
money thing doesn't happen as much
nowadays but sometimes it still does on
the private ones so
um Jesus Christ okay so this is more
than 10 years ago because I'm having to
scroll all the way down yeah it's crazy
yeah uh let's see here what was the
first one
um
on two hands maybe one even one hand
yeah the number yeah that have bugs
going back 10 years yeah hold on that's
crazy yeah so um yeah so I started doing
bug crowd during the nights when I was
doing pen testing during the day for HP
sure and um really the guy who really
made made me obsessive with it was
bicork
um he's another really great hacker in
the scene
and uh so we were we were neck and neck
in the leaderboard for for like a year
basically up and down and up and down
um and honestly he's a you know he's
he's one of the best hackers in the
world if you ever meet this guy I think
Quirk is uh you know a great guy I've
met him at Defcon and um he likes to
keep his privacy but he was very very
technical and um but we battled for like
a year on the leaderboard when bug crowd
you know even first launched you right
yeah so exactly 10 years the first one I
participated in uh was 10 years ago my
first Bounty you guys want to know what
my first Bounty was hit us hit us with
it are you guys gonna laugh all right
100 and five points for missing HTTP
cooking flag no
right
I know dude I know you know it's uh my
first uh my first big one was a web
application firewall bypass
um
so that one was I think it was a
WordPress WAFF that they had implemented
and you could add uh a header that
basically said like you know gave it
like a address of 127001 and it wouldn't
apply checks to you anymore nice um
that's that's crazy though because you
know I guess at that time you know the
standards were kind of still being
established for what exactly pug Downey
was morphing into yeah exactly yeah in
this modern day area you know era we're
kind of in this place of like POC or
gtfl yeah exactly yeah have very
exploitable drugs but in the beginning
you know it was it was the closest thing
to it was a pen test exactly and and so
you know why wouldn't you report I mean
I was reporting I mean that's something
I learned right away right like so the
bug Bounty it morphed pretty quickly to
like hey the stuff you're gonna report
uh as information on the pen test should
really not be reported to a bug Bounty
like it's just it's not something they
really care about or they've seen it
before or whatever but in back in the
day honestly like even some people were
not talking about like
cookie security right or like or header
security and so like this was pretty
Cutting Edge 10 years ago so people were
like oh yeah I can mitigate you know
certain portions of sea Surf and cross
that request forgery if I just set this
cookie and I was like well why don't I
report it right if they want to take it
they'll take it and if they don't want
to take it they won't and so some like I
continue to do this for like months and
some people did and some people were
like nah that's cool and like you know
like a lot of my bigger bugs you know in
the Years following were obviously like
you know like SQL injection and stuff
like that if I'm scrolling up here but
um I don't know why but like
I just I cannot find a SQL injection
like I I found you know I've been doing
this full-time for three years and I've
been hacking you know six years you know
so I've real experienced over here but
um uh you know I found maybe like it's
just one of those bugs that always gets
gets past me I've found like five or six
SQL injections in my so that's like one
a year for my whole career yeah I just I
don't know I just maybe it's the targets
maybe it's my testing methodology but
whenever anybody says yeah you know what
my one of my main bugs is SQL injections
I'm like really like are you sure like
oh yeah yeah it's it was more prevalent
back then for sure I feel like SQL
injections almost solved I think at this
point and yeah you know I think I think
there's also this thing that people
don't talk about is like
um there are generations of hackers now
right so there are people who've grown
up with Cloud first and um and newer
languages and Frameworks that you know
these bugs are all but extinct in in
this new stuff but when you get on a
program that's Legacy man I wreck those
programs because I grew up in those
Technologies right like Java and stuff
like that and like and they still have
SQL injection all over the place because
like no one's audited that code in eight
million years especially if it's closed
source so right
um yeah I mean it it is funny because
like uh you know like when I get on like
like when I know an old a program is um
is based on like an older technology or
framework or or as a legacy company
um which you know many of the bigger
companies in the world are you know
still carrying Legacy technology
um you know you still find some of that
kind of stuff so yeah yeah for sure I I
know who to Ping now when I get a cool
private
Legacy program yeah so um yeah so I
worked at Bud crowd uh battled it out
for leaderboard spot number one I think
that was in 2016 and 2017 and maybe a
little bit of 2018 and then bug Bounty
blew up
um and I went to work for bug crowd
because I want to be involved in it and
uh that just I mean did you just hit
Casey up and be like hey man I'm loving
this or do they hit you up or how did
that go
um so I met him at Defcon they flew me
out uh for being the number one
researcher and I got to meet like Franz
and on instrument and some other really
cool people
for the first time bit quark and um
and I was like yeah I want to be
involved in this I told Casey I'm like
how you know like how can I work for you
guys and they needed a head of the
triage team basically ahead of
operations and um I was like yeah I
could do that I mean it wasn't it wasn't
too unsimilar for managing a pen test
team honestly
um and I wanted to build like a
world-class pen you know triage team
they say that to you right they say hey
we need a head of triage yeah what's
going through your head at this point
because like so you're currently
employed or no or yeah yeah I'm employed
yeah you're doing bug Daddy on the side
you know I I don't know
you know what kind of money you were
making at the time but when I was
employed and I was doing punk Bounty
there was a point where my bug Bounty
income surpassed my my main income right
and I was like okay I need to like I
need to go full-time bug Bounty because
there's no reason for me to be doing
this
um but if I were to have hacker one or
bug crowd or you know any of these
programs uh or these platforms reach out
to me and say hey Justin we want you to
come do XYZ but you can't hack
yeah that was that was part of the
agreement yeah yeah so they
um basically the rule I mean there
wasn't hard and soft policies back then
but
um the rule once I came on I was the
first kind of tester that they had you
know running an operations team and so
any program I had access to I wasn't
allowed to hack on
um which was a lot of programs because
uh we hadn't built out a just-in-time
access system like you know back then it
was like you know you would get invites
and it was like oh crap I have you know
like because I'm in a marketing role and
an operations role and like I you know
I'm talking these customers all the time
so I guess that means I can't hack on
these things so it really did stop my
hunting for like a year and a half until
they came out you know with um with some
stuff and some new policies and then I
could get back to hacking but
um you know like that's a lot of the
things a lot of people don't talk about
honestly is that you know people like us
who have full-time security jobs and or
bug bounty hunting also take Moonlight
work and my Moonlight pen test work was
able to keep me through you know just
doing side pen tests for people
um was able to replace that Bounty kind
of uh money that makes sense I mean I
guess maybe I should I should hit Casey
up and ask Kevin this question but I
feel like it's a little bit of a I feel
like it's a little bit of an odd move as
a startup to take your top hacker and
then employ him and then say now you
can't hack like I don't know I feel like
that's a little bit of a weird move
because at that point they still need to
sell their product and yeah for for them
you know you are one of the main selling
I mean you pretty much like I would
imagine at that point you know some high
percentage of the the bugs being
submitted are you and so they kind of
cut that that you know contributions to
the platform out when they employed you
and obviously they gained a lot of other
benefits and and stuff like that but I
don't know it's what do you think about
that decision so slow him down at all or
my final position at HP before I left
was director of penetration testing at
HP
um which was a giant role and carried
with it a lot of clout because I think
the only director of penetration testing
in the world was Dan Kaminsky at that
time at Io active wow
um and so
um
[Music]
Fanboy in a little bit here
um and so I they definitely gained more
than they lost right yeah uh because I
am really good at you know basically
marketing and sales and all this other
stuff but you know I think for many many
years you know it was like oh Jason
Haddix is involved in bug crowd let's go
check them out and see what they're
about and I know the triage team he's
leading that so it must be really good
and
um so I think it far outweighed you know
my my my bug hunting contributions so
okay so you had enough of a clout in the
community at that point yeah to to be
able to transition you know over to bug
crowd and then you know use that
position to help bug crowd sort of sell
the product and get in it very that
makes sense that makes sense all right
Casey all right I don't mean to call you
out Casey like you know you knew what
you were doing no Casey Casey's actually
so brilliant I mean um yeah he's not
he's not front and center in a lot of
stuff but he's one of the smartest
entrepreneurs I've ever met honestly uh
and I would work I would work with him
again in a second at a new at a new
Venture if you know if anything ever
happened but
um Casey's my bro so anyway so I worked
at bug crowd for five years
um and then uh you know I went through a
number of roles I went through the
operations director of operations and
then to head of trust and security which
is a hybrid security role
um and then our sales engineering leader
left
um and then I stepped in to basically on
sales engineering
um which I stayed in for a year and a
half because I was really good at it
um and then I left that role to go to
researcher's success and I was head of
uh research enablement basically which
was to basically grow kind of uh the
number of good hackers on bug crowd uh
and to compete with kind of the
marketing spend that hacker one spends
on like really pushing the hacker faces
out there we wanted to you know do the
same stuff and so created the ambassador
program created the free education
helped create level up
um you know pushed our conference and
marketing kind of agenda our open source
tools all of that I was I was doing all
that that's kind of the position I
remember you from you know yeah that's
my that's my intro yeah I was at that
point yeah so so at what point did you
start like had you already started
working on the bug Benny like hackers
like methodology at that point or yeah I
um so I did the first version of what I
would call uh the bug Hunters
methodology talk
um at Defcon 16 I think and
um and it was back then it was called
how to shot web
um
yeah yeah and so it was it was the it
was in Defcon 101 tracks and
um it was you know it was it was not as
refined as it is now but
um yeah I mean back then a lot of people
weren't really talking about Recon and
even really in-depth kind of web things
that we take for granted now right so
like
um you know look at a new school
Frameworks probably got payloads you
know file upload vulnerabilities were
still everywhere you know and so I just
started talking to friends and parsing
like every blog I could and just put it
into this presentation that I was like
hey if you're a web tester you know
maybe you'll find something useful in
this giant dump of information and and
uh people really really really responded
to it I got hundreds of messages like
that's the best web presentation I've
seen all year and I was like all right
cool so maybe I'll just do this every
year and I'll talk about bug classes and
tools that save time for pen testers and
Bug hunters and and that's kind of what
the talk morphed into and
um yeah so that's when I started that
talk that's awesome man yeah it's just
such a legendary piece and when you when
you said how to shot web I just got
flooded by Nostalgia like I definitely
went back and looked into that and said
yeah yeah that was really cool yeah
um so I left I left bug crowd went on to
Ubisoft as the CSO um wanted to try my
hand at like the big org CSO role and
that was uh that was a lot of fun I did
a lot of really great work there with
some tremendous people
um you know lived through you know
working three years at Ubisoft was like
working 10 years at any other company
um because it was Giants it was 22 000
people
um the the uh the thing is that uh we
were one Central Security Group managing
all of those people who are primarily
devs it was still hybrid Legacy
um so a lot of security issues to take
care of a lot of Security Programs to
run and then honestly the hardest thing
about the gaming industry
um is that each game in it of itself is
like a product team and so if you can
imagine having one company with 60
products and you have to secure them it
is insane
um and you learn so much because they're
not standardized they're each their own
Tech stack infrastructure some people
building their own stuff some people are
using cloud and it's like okay so you're
a group of you know 50 to 100 people but
you have 60 products to secure it's a
it's amazingly drinking from the fire
hose yeah it's crazy wow yeah that that
I couldn't even imagine you know that
level of dealing with that many
employees and that many products there's
nuts all right so I did that I enjoyed
it
um but then I left and now I am at a
place called butterbot okay tell me a
bit about that and actually that that's
headquartered in in Virginia right yes
it is yeah right where are you at
currently I'm in Colorado okay oh yeah
yeah that's right you're in Colorado
dude you know Virginia welcomes you man
okay all right get over here I'm I'm
trying to sell Joel on moving over here
in the works it's uh it's a nice place I
like it a lot so
um
yeah I mean we moved to Colorado just
because uh we need a bigger space for
the fam right we wanted every kid to
have a room and I wanted a basement that
was kind of sound isolated to do stuff
like this so
um that's and we chose Colorado but uh
but yeah so butterbot
like I said I lived through my
Moonlighting sometimes
um and you know made extra income and I
always moonlighted with this company
called butterbot with a friend of mine
Luke who built this company oh nice and
um he's been you know he's been doing
this for 10 years but on the dod side so
DOD pen test DOD security Contracting
um it has a really great relationship
with a lot of the three letter agencies
and so I would come on and do these
tests for him
and then you know off board and we
always really work together and so uh
this last year he was like hey do you
want to come and really push this thing
into the you know the regular
Enterprises of the world uh and build
out you know like uh kind of a a little
bit of um a regression but also like a
Way Forward
um in security testing I was like yeah
so I'll come and Lead it so um so I am
now the ciso butterbot but really I'm
doing everything it's you know we're
about on this side we're about you know
15 to 20 people
um and so we're doing full scope
adversary emulation so one thing I
learned at uh at Ubisoft uh with the
lapsis incident that happened and just
like living in that world talking to cso
friends is that there's a giant
disconnect between bug Bounty and
penetration testing and what actually
causes an incident absolutely um at a
company and so adversaries like yeah
they do take advantage of application
infrastructure bugs uh but more often
than not they're using phishing they're
using configuration like you know bugs
um or the other bugs that you haven't
turned off right yeah exactly yeah
um but the actually one of the biggest
ones is is just like they're not even
doing the work themselves all the time
right so like they're going to Dark Net
markets and picking up credentials and
doing credential stuffing and using them
in novel ways and
um the more and more I talked to csos
last year I was like yeah I mean there's
a couple red team companies that do full
scope stuff like this but there's not
many and I really I really think that
you know from seeing everything at my
time at Ubisoft that someone needs to
offer a full scope service so what we do
at butterbot is we do like a a year long
we call it continuous adversary
emulation it's a year-long service
um so we scope the project do Recon up
front for the external we do so year of
testing
um basically for you and that's like I
mean is that the go-to product or is
that the minimum product or like that's
like that's the premium product yeah
okay that's the premium product okay
yeah that's what you're trying to you
you know yeah you may you may you know
people say hey I can't handle you know a
year of protesting budget wise to kind
of scale it off but yeah that's that's
the that's the product that you're
trying to get out there yeah I mean the
the general narrative is basically that
you know like hackers don't really take
a break right and it's YP a lot of
people pivot to bug Bounty right
um you know a lot of the times but um so
we're offering Advanced social
engineering with it we're going to the
dark web we're pulling creds off of
things like genesis market and stuff
like that so we bake in a whole bunch of
threat intelligence we also do attack
surface management so I basically took
everything that I thought you know what
are real adversaries doing these days to
get in from the external and how can I
turn that into a service and then I also
took kind of my 15 years of internal
penetration testing and red teaming and
so we do we do about eight externals
over the course of 12 months and two
internals and we turn it into the
service called
um continuous adversary emulation and
then we bake in some stuff at the end
too to do atomic red team testing and I
was just like hey if you were a
mid-sized company and you couldn't
afford a red team like Google has right
what would be the package that you would
want to really figure out if you could
be breached and we built that into a
service so that's kind of where we are
now that's crazy that that sounds like
such a a valuable product to the
customer like that that and I think it's
so awesome that you're a part of
crafting that too because you have such
a eclectic experience you started in I.T
then you moved into pen testing so you
got the internal external pen testing
side you've done bug Bounty which is
just outside your GTFO your kind of csos
you've seen all the attacks the CSO have
a breached company yes you can see the
see all the attacks and the attack
vectors and then you take all that
experience roll it up into one service
and give it to the medium-sized
companies that can't afford their own
red team yep exactly and it's all and
it's usually for the price of what you
would spend on like you know one red
team or two so it's like uh pretty
affordable but like yeah it's times like
this times like this when I hear about
this product that I'm like
[Laughter]
yes I get in there and I'm like hackity
hackity and it's like I just love it so
but then I hear about stuff like this
and I'm like wow that is so and and
don't get me wrong book Downey has a lot
of value ads oh yeah I totally believe
that product yeah but when I hear about
stuff like this and my entrepreneurial
side just starts going and like my just
give amazing value to companies yeah
it's going and it just gets me hyped man
yeah so one of the things that we add
into
um we call it CAE or whatever but
um is actually we we're looking for a
better name but we call it the ringer
and um the ringer is bringing in one of
you guys twice a year so My Team of
Engineers will uh will do you know our
best and we will do a lot of Recon up
front to figure out the Technologies
whether they're SAS or you know
infrastructure or whatever
um and then as part of the built-in cost
for the year-long service we bring in
two specialized bug bounty hunters to
work with us on our butterbot team for
three weeks and we pay them up front
it's not pay for effort so yeah yeah
um yeah yeah uh and so
um I'm building a small you know small
stable of people I really trust who are
world-class Engineers who can come on
and just like be those extra eyes and uh
who I know are Specialists and
technology and you know I know bug
bounty hunters have been asking for this
you know for a long time right I mean
hacker one and Bug crowd have their
crowdsource pen test but this is this is
a lot of fun um and I'm really only
inviting people I know who are super
legit and um you know like I've got
Brett on speed dial for some stuff and
uh yeah
and uh you know zlz and you know I'm
obviously thinking about you guys but
yeah you know bounty hunters are getting
tired of the of the waste on my time and
not get paid and get [__] around by
the platform
um you know kind of thing and we're
gonna give it back to the bug bounty
hunters and let them get paid for their
effort and work with the cool team and
be an extension of our team here because
I know the power of that and so yeah uh
I mean like you know bug Bounty
platforms look out I'm coming for you
that's all I gotta say
all right I feel it though and I think I
think there definitely is I mean
in in a lot of ways the attack surface
is getting harder
um in a lot of ways it's getting easier
and there's there's there's a trade-off
you know a lot more companies are
getting into bug Bounty so there's a lot
more places to hack and a lot more
things to go after but yeah you know as
we evolve the pub classes are starting
sort of Disappearing xssi was I loved
exercise and that that's that's gone now
and yeah and csrf is still possible but
you know it's definitely a struggle now
yeah um and so you know as we see these
attack surfaces sort of
um showing up a little bit we have to
Pivot and and I think another big thing
that would be really helpful for bug
bounty hunters are especially people
that want to do like solo entrepreneur
stuff is like have this thing with with
Jason where you know you go and you do
your Moonlighting and you you know do
some Pen test-like work and that assures
you you're going to make your however
much yeah your base or whatever yeah
like you know make sure you're paying
your bills and you know feeding your
family and that sort of thing and then
you get to spend your time you get your
freedom you get your you know To Be Your
Own Boss and you know you can go after
whatever other targets you find
interesting in the bug Bounty space and
would do whatever research you want to
do which is where I find a lot of value
in being a full-time book Bounty Hunter
yeah absolutely and um you know like we
were we were really hyped because uh you
know like the bug bounty hunters are
really good on the externals but a lot
of bug bounty hunters don't get a lot of
internal work so like the active
directory type of exploitation I miss
that man and uh and you know we we do
two of those you know in the package a
year or if we can pivot from external
internal we find a bug that lets us do
that obviously we start doing that type
of work and we do yeah we do two types
and so like being able to work with you
know some of the bug bounty hunters on
like getting back into that skill set
they're just like oh this is refreshing
I get to do this kind of stuff and
um yeah it's pretty it's pretty cool so
yeah it absolutely is all right all
right so that's that's the intro for you
um Joel where do you want to go from
here dude well I have like it's you have
such a really diverse like full
background it's really really
interesting to hear I think I I
definitely relate with a lot of the
types of experiences that you've been
through going from like Hacker's side to
like corporate side and I'm very much so
like on the corporate side currently and
it's just very interesting to hear you
talk about sort of
um a lot of the things that everybody
within like corporate security sort of
talks about where it's like yeah you
know bug Bounty is a thing that exists
but it's like not a one size fits-all
solution and it doesn't solve all the
problems it solves like a select portion
of the problems and like it doesn't
create a security team it doesn't create
a cultural security within a company are
you trying to tell me that I I the bug
Bounty Hunter and not the end-all be-all
what are you what are you talking about
not to invalidate you too much
yeah so no it's really cool to hear that
like you've taken all that like
experience and stuff and like turned it
into something that you can help like
provide to companies I was curious is
the only thing that um butterbot like
provides is it purely sort of that like
testing side or do you also provide like
almost application security as a service
or that type of like guidance towards
how to build better security teams and
all that kind of stuff so uh one of the
things that I'm like really really good
at and it does not really like a bug
Bounty skill but is like off-boarding
and onboarding customers
um because I've you know at bug crowd I
worked with probably over 250
you know programs and then at HP I've
worked with the majority of the Fortune
100 and so um and you know some of my
best friends are vcsos which jump in and
out of companies all the time so I have
a very good pulse on like how to help
them build a security program so in in
the reporting and you know this is a new
company right so we're still building
out how this works but in the
off-boarding a whole month is dedicated
with the head of the security program
the sock
um you know whatever their team
structure is like right if it's I.T or
whatever on
um building the right security program
it with the focus of to not get breached
basically right like I I really
appreciate application security and
product security and all the other
portions of security and Security
Programs and stuff like that but really
like the point of the service is like
can you get breached right like because
that's the nightmare for the CSO is is
like getting wrecked
um and I've had that nightmare so I know
um yeah uh so yeah um that's the point
of it is mostly testing but at the end
we offer like a month of kind of
off-boarding and it includes some
security and like I said we include
things like if we have a successful
attack path we're going to do atomic red
team and atomic purple team test what
does that mean what is atomic
so you can think of the miter attack
framework which is a lot of what pen
testers and red teamers use these days
to describe micro pieces of their
methodology on how they basically
achieve their objectives and the way
they do it is they take real threat
actors and they break down their
methodologies into tiny little ttps
basically and miter attack Maps out all
those types and individual tests and so
uh basically uh Atomic red team tests
are small little bite size code pieces a
lot of times in Powershell but sometimes
in other Technologies that'll allow you
to replay one tiny little portion of
attack to see if your sock can recognize
it or train them on recognizing it
um training training The Blue Team to
see various attacks while they're
happening exactly yes and so uh you know
so you sit with them and you're like hey
I'm gonna push the button right now do
you see it in Splunk and they're like
yeah I saw it like okay let's build that
alert and let's prioritize it you know
correctly and you know how do you scale
that across a 22 000 person business and
like you know so you you kind of build
out parts of their defensive nature
um but will they be for you know will we
be fixing code level vulnerabilities
probably not I want to give I want to
give my customers the best I can but I'm
probably not going to consult with them
and you know fix app level code bugs
I'll show you I'll give them as much
advice as I can but yeah that's kind of
where we'll be at so I I'd imagine and
Joel you can probably shed some more
light on this but I'd imagine that you
know bringing in a third party to
actually modify your code base and stuff
like that I feel like that it's a little
bit you know like because you got to
kind of know the context of the
application and then you've gotta you've
got all this you know learning friction
that you've got
um you know if you're bringing on a
third party actually fix the code base
so I mean do you do you see that Joel I
mean yeah I mean I've had discussions
about this with um some of our mutual
friends about like
does it make sense to think about
starting like a company that's basically
abstract as a service or project as a
service and the conclusion I came to is
not really because an abstract team
needs to be bespoke it needs to be
highly integrated it needs to be like
well-versed with the engineering team
and like what they're doing and what the
infrastructure looks like and what the
systems look like and what means
sensitive to that company and you can
you can contract that out to some extent
but actually building like a
full-fledged security team that has
trust with the engineers and can like
make actual improvements throughout the
whole ecosystem it's really difficult
from an outside perspective okay so I'm
going to show my I'm going to show my
true you know red team side here and
having done you know maybe a year of Dev
work but outside of that none so the
security teams at these organizations
this I'll throw this to both of you but
I want to hear from from Joel first year
and then go over to Jason because he's
got a wider variety of experience does
the security team actually have like can
you go in there and modify code or do
you have to be like devs please change
this please please you know like how
does that work so so at least where I
work
um no it's all like you have to you
would have to request like right access
to those repos to be able to like write
and even still like the most you could
do is probably open like a pull request
you couldn't actually make changes on on
Main or anything like that
um and I think that's like definitely
for the better obviously okay I don't
think you really want your application
security team to be pulling like into
that space and trying to like become the
engineers right because that's not
really what their specialty is yeah we
could make code changes that would
probably be valid but like that also
means we have to learn like this repo
and the syntaxes and all the different
coding you know whatever like
documentation and best practices that
they follow within that team or that
repo or whatever and we could try and
replicate that but the amount of time it
would take for us to do that versus
saying here's what you should do and let
the engineer who knows what they're
doing go ahead and take that we've
always found that it's easier to just
like guide and then like just verify
right Jason do you do you see that same
thing
um I mean so if you break it into two
it's like is there opportunity for a
consultancy to do that uh usually not
I've had a couple friends who tried to
bake it in and
um like on board as longer term projects
and bacon application security but there
is always a culture Clash of being a
consultant
um and so it usually doesn't work like
that but there's some examples that are
you know like positive at least I can
think of but
um as far as internally and the way you
structure your security team so one of
the things I was really successful at
and I got this advice from a
um a security leader friend of mine uh
Tony who used to be a Tinder
um but uh Tony was like the best thing I
ever do was create a Central Security
engineering organization
um and so that's what I did at Ubisoft
is I you know one of the four brand big
branches of our security team was this
um kind of uh pick up the bat phone this
is a priority application bring on
um four or five appsec engineers and
they've been on board with you for six
months at a time and basically be part
of your team and they you know they they
got billed to your team and so they
would sit with you they would go to
stand ups you know they're part of the
you know all of the you know Dev
infrastructure and everything like that
and then they would start fixing
vulnerabilities themselves after
um you know a little while and then we
would have to do that by priority
because we had 60 products but
eventually we started burning down
really really big systemic issues and
then we can move on to categories of
non-systemic issues that were priority
and then to medium priority and so we
had this like Strike Team that we could
apply and it was you know it became very
very very successful inside of Ubisoft
and so I think that whole org was broken
up into uh security engineering was
broken up into security Architects which
helped design systematic fixes basically
um which you know we had we had two
Cloud Architects on different
Technologies we had kind of our Legacy
Technologies guy we had a guy who knew
the network really well and like the
topology we had an API guy and then we
had a couple guys who were just devs in
the coding languages of whatever
um that we you know most of our
Productions used and then we had a
consultant team who were trainers and
threat modelers and they would on board
with products and um and then we had
um we had a couple other like just like
people on the team but I think it was a
total team of maybe 15
and they helped a lot of people in that
model 2000 yeah yeah yeah but I mean it
can make a big impact honestly so
um yeah so they they onboarded and were
really successful and I like that Strike
Team type of mentality
um you know if you have the budget for
it inside of an organization very cool
so would you say that there are like any
like major key takeaways that you
still pull on like on a day-to-day basis
from like your hacker experience going
into like a c-suite experience and then
also from like your preview like running
a security team to now being like head
of security
uh yeah absolutely I would I mean
there's a ton of valuable lessons in
fact
um I get myself in trouble a lot uh
because I call a lot of csos haha csos
or business csos
at conferences and stuff because they've
never actually done security I mean
they'll come from like Risk Management
or they'll come from you know some have
come from like marketing or something
like that it's like these are Executives
and having the executive skill set and
being able to present to the board and
speak well is absolutely a key feature
you need you know to be in this in this
role but I I believe the future lies
with technical csos people who
understand at at least like a medium
level uh what the attacks are and
um and you know you use that to guide
your security program so I you know I
was on a panel a couple weeks ago here
in Denver with you know two guys who
were very eloquent they dress very
nicely I'm in my hoodie up there on
stage and they're talking about like all
these Security Programs and I'm like man
I would just not invest in that right
that's not a thing that's going to get
us breached like that is a thing that
like I guess you you're you're running
metrics on just to make yourself feel
good right
um and so yeah it's not practical it's
not practical at all yeah um and so like
yeah I get in trouble because I call
them haha csos
um I I when I worked at a at a previous
my previous consultancy I worked for
Center Comm in Wisconsin also do
something very similar by the way to
your your you know full scale
um you know simulation of uh adversaries
nice um but I I went with them to RSA
you know and I I was at the booth you
know talking to people and stuff like
that and I can't tell you how many times
people came over and were like wow look
at this guy he's like actually talking
about like his own attack vectors and
stuff like that and so on one of my
breaks I was kind of walking around and
like looking at some of the other places
there and there's just so many like
crapo products out there man oh yeah
it's like and or and even if the product
has Merit you know there's there the
people that are there you know doing the
talking and stuff like that you know if
you try to poke a little bit deeper at a
technical level it gets a little bit
tricky so it is definitely refreshing to
see
um you know someone technical in those
positions and I think it's also fairly
rare as well you know
um yeah but it's I also feel like it's
not as after being in the bug Bounty
Community after going to the live
hacking events I also feel like it's not
as rare as people make it out to be like
got you know we're we're all we're all
hackers we're doing our hackity thing
but like a decent amount of the people
at the life hacking events are also like
really cool yeah really eloquent and
like really like well spoken and all of
the like show and tells that happen are
like really well done uh you know most
of the time and so um I think there's
definitely some space for uh you know
hackers to be
utilized in in sales and marketing a
little bit oh yeah stronger and and I'm
just you know whether it aligns with
their goals or not or their desires or
not that's a different story but yeah um
the capability is definitely there I
think yeah I think that um I think
specifically Joel on the questions like
you know what specifically translated
um it was more focused on like the
technical bugs that I thought could lead
to both breaches of private information
and uh and you know breaches from
external internal I really wanted that
also the
um although it's a saturated Market I
feel because it all came from bug Bounty
but you know having a risk register and
an asset identification plan is really
important to organizations so like you
know Tax Service management and stuff
like that right like if you think about
like how much stuff gets found in the
bug Bounty scene because of Recon and
Recon came out of bug Bounty and now
it's like this you know multi-million
dollar industry that platforms are
spawning up around and so
um you know like I think that's
important like you can't defend what you
don't know about in a security program
so like you have to have
um you know some kind of centralized
place and yeah so I'm a I'm a big fan
there vulnerability like strict
vulnerability management I didn't think
was as important until I married the two
goals right like nothing's worse than
just having a backlog full of bugs
you're never going to fix right it has
to be prioritized it has to be clean
um these are all things that you have to
have a strong program around which bug
Bounty is a portion of finding
vulnerabilities right so it fits in
there under vulnerability management and
operations and
um and then I think
you know I I think just uh also
um
like what else did I bring from my
hacker life I don't know yeah I was
gonna say so like we're all about the
technical stuff here and this is not one
of the questions that we you know I sent
to you beforehand so no no sorry
but like for example you know you said
focusing on practices that are going to
limit you know personal information
disclosure and stuff like that so are we
talking about like okay we need we have
to get rid of these numeric IDs and
switch to uuids or we you know we have
to uh you know install Access Control at
like a middleware or something like that
I don't know you know what the practices
there are because once again I'm I'm a
hacker not not a Dev but like you know
we're talking about those sort of things
yeah I mean where where Paul okay well I
mean the first thing that's going to
reduce like anything at a security
program when you drop in as a VC Source
see so right is is authentication
changes which is two-factor
authentication if you can get fito
rolling a number of breaches you know I
would say I'm gonna say 80 or more have
some sort of credential reuse component
to them these days and so you focus hard
on that although a lot of people love to
hate it in DDR if you don't have an EDR
strategy you got to have some sort of
EDR
um and uh you know a lot of people have
done Sim two but you got it like there
are table Stakes for a security program
but when you come with an offensive
mindset yes you get into the cloud world
you get into
IAM for cloud you get into configuration
management for cloud you get into yes
architecting systems where you're not uh
doing access control
um badly you know which means like
mitigating a lot of idor type attacks
um you know in a video game company
specifically we had to focus a lot on
not leaking
data that was pre-release or
post-release but private you know that
could help cheaters and stuff like that
so
um we focused a lot on on cloud leaks
and stuff like that so um yeah that's
cool man and and I appreciate giving
giving that context even though it's
kind of a surprise question and the the
topical pieces are always really really
you know once you get your eyes on it
you start seeing the holes but it's not
necessarily like you know Jason opens up
his little book and he's like all right
you know you know every numeric ID needs
to be you know yeah no no you got to
take it piece by piece right yeah yeah
so I wanted to dive in on on some of the
like Recon and assets Discovery stuff
you were talking about but yeah before
we did that I actually wanted to just
ask about one thing that we had briefly
talked about which is
um you know the skill within sort of the
hacker Community right so like we're all
hackers um I think we all know a ton of
like really really talented people from
the bug Bounty space especially yeah
um and having like
transition from hacking to like
full-time back to hacking hacking and
full-time all that kind of stuff yeah
like do you have any tips on like how to
hire some of those amazing talent
sources like how do you pull someone
into the like corporate space how do you
get them to go full time yeah I mean um
You Gotta Give so people who are
full-time bug Bounty who are really
really good
uh sometimes come with you know
personality and so you've got to be a
manager who can foster personality I
think
um and let them kind of spread their
wings uh I was I won't say which job it
was but
um one of my jobs right like like I am
very add and um and I will go off on
like some project and dive really deep
into it and then like you know like uh
but it might not be the thing I'm
supposed to be doing at that time and so
people uh one of the people at my work
put up this sign in their office and
they said let Jason be Jason uh it was
actually let Jay Haddix be J Haddix
um that's awesome and
um and so you got to kind of treat
people like that right like you know
like let them focus on as long as
they're bringing value with their focus
you got to let them uh you know spread
their wings I mean as far as monetary
right it's really hard because some of
those people when they are ready to
transition they're looking at I don't
know if you guys talk about money on on
this but I mean they're I mean you're
looking at like a a world-class bug
Bounty Hunter is not going to take a job
a company for less than two hundred
fifty thousand dollars and sometimes
were some of the fan companies or Maga
companies now whatever they're called
um that's 500k uh total package you know
and sometimes maybe even base you know
450 and then total package is like 600
700 800 plus you know you've got crazy
bonuses every year
um they're just really expensive some of
the great talent and so like if you're
looking to bring in someone like that
but you're not one of those companies
you got to have an epic culture you got
to have interesting clients you got to
have an epic service right that allows
them to learn and grow you got to have
leadership who understands them
um and uh you know that's kind of what
I'm trying to build at butterbot right
is like uh you know hopefully I'll see
some of the new up and coming you know
bug Hunters come work for us and be
offensive security Engineers
um and you got to offer stability too
right like if you can't meet the package
what what are things that you can do
that can't meet package of like a Google
right and that is like it's portions of
culture it's you know like I did this
whole talk on
um on how to but when we were in the
great basically uh resignation phase
last year before we were into the great
firing phase now
um I did a talk at black hat at the ciso
summit and it was it was like how to
basically keep your employees in an Ever
competitive market and you know at
Shadow Labs you know we had this great
program where we would induct people
into Shadow Labs once a year at an
awards ceremony we'd give them all this
badass swag very similar to what hacker
one does at a live event but it was
exclusive it was for your contribution
to the team we were doing hack Fridays
we focused we over indexed on training
each other and being like a family
um and like those are intangibles right
like and they cost nearly nothing
honestly like swag is a is a penny on
the dollar compared to you know anything
and really right I'm not gonna lie right
like
you see people walking around bug crowd
or hacker ones hoodies or people who
work at really reputable shops you know
who do pen testing or whatever and they
have these Brands and you would be
surprised at how powerful those brands
are to make you feel included and like
family and accepted because we're all
nerds right and we all have these small
little quirks of like you know like am I
good enough we all have imposter
syndrome
um and uh and so if you can cultivate
that vibe that family
um you know Cutting Edge Vibe you can
get some of those people against Google
and Netflix and you know those places
and stuff like that yeah man I I have to
say like that that Ring's so true for me
and I I tell you so I worked at
centercon before I mentioned them before
um in Wisconsin and like I like I said
you know I was it's it's a smaller
consultancy and I was I was making you
know a good amount for a junior pen
tester you know because they got me
right out of college traded right there
and uh but you know my bounty income
you know quickly started surpassing that
yeah and but I didn't I didn't leave for
a while and um and the reason why is is
just like it was just such a good
Community it was such a great place to
work and like the people that I was
around were awesome and so at the end
when I I did leave the reason I left was
because uh it was Mariah's dream my
wife's dream to move to Japan and um you
know I couldn't keep the same schedule
you know work schedule if I was in Japan
so I was like right you know I'm gonna
pull the trigger and go yeah but um that
was one of the hardest things I've ever
done man they're like it was so hard
leaving that company and yeah and um and
so yeah I think there's definitely it's
definitely possible you know speaking
from a full-time boat Bounty perspective
you know if you can if you can entice
that if you can show that amount of
um culture that amount of you know I
don't know there's just a good feel I
don't know how to describe it but
there's a good feel then you can really
pull the talent for sure yes I pulled I
pulled up some of the slides from the
talk right so usually the things that
are set in stone for a company trying to
attract are base range Equity range
yearly bonus and benefits those are kind
of set in stones for the company you
know you know that them before going
into negotiation but what are negotiated
what are negotiated really is hiring
bonus so you can you can usually
negotiate a higher hiring bonus for
someone
um uh PTO right like PTO actually can be
negotiated right like how much actual
time after you get to cut off you know a
year uh work from home obviously is a
big one nowadays right like the promise
to to stay in your own space if you want
to you know uh four day work week is
becoming more and more popular like uh
you know to have that three-day weekend
also is pretty baller I've done it
before where it's big man yeah you get
to spend a lot more time with your
family like a bigger chunk with your
family and then like intrinsic is like
how much travel training are you going
to make people do
um you know the the idea of the 80 20
work uh work project kind of cycle that
Google does right 80 time on your job 20
time of your time can be spent on
building tools or contributing the
community another way or learning
um and then I'm just a big component of
flex time which a lot of people don't
like but um a lot of like managing
people don't like but I like as long as
you're doing your work if you if you
ever call me and I'm your boss and
you're like hey I'm gonna I'm gonna go
to like you know like do this cool thing
that just came up right I'm like yeah go
do it like you know like take the day
off take you know tomorrow off or
whatever as long as we're getting our
projects done and our deliverables done
and you don't have like a a thing like I
just consider that some nights I'm
working until like 10 o'clock you know
because I'm in the zone I'm you know I'm
going you know like and I don't want to
stop working and so people talk about
this hustle and grind mentality but I
think of it more as like flexible time
right where you can put in you know
maybe 10 hours one day and then only put
into another day and in actuality Tech
workers work like that anyway so just
making it official is like is is such a
relief for many people they're just like
oh Jason Jason knows I want to go to
this Rave thing and like I'm gonna be
back in a couple days and I'm not gonna
have my phone on he'll cover for me and
like
um you know or something like that and
then mentorship is the last one I have
in my list is just like strong
mentorship like you know Joel's on my
team and he wants to be the CSO level
right like I am going to meet with Joel
every week and be like where are we with
your goals to get to this level that you
want to get to how can I help you you
know where do I have feedback and
mentorship is really really big and the
leaders spending time mentoring is
really important like you have to take
the time out of your day to Mentor
people otherwise they will they will you
know become disconnected basically dang
man that's that's gold that's I mean
that was like a little mini master class
and how to be a game
fire dude I will say yeah
the flex time
let's jump back to that like I I
recently so as a as a full-time bike
bounty hunter I've had a couple of my
friends that are are wanting to make the
jump
um hit me up and be like hey can we set
sit down have a chat you know and figure
out whether this is the right fit for me
I was like sure so we I get on a call
with them and um
one of the things you know I talk to
these people like you said you know
salaries are pretty good yeah and some
of these companies and you know you can
make a chunk as a full-time poke Bounty
Hunter if you're if you're skilled for
sure
um even more so it then you know
probably what I would be getting in the
industry right now if I went and worked
as in you know in just with my
experience level and such like that but
um you know the big thing for me is is
the flex is the flexibility right yeah
um and so you know I'm talking to these
guys and I'm like hey you know what well
what's the what's the value add for
going
um you know full-time back Bounty for
you so let's let's assume the money is
roughly the same you know for your first
year you know you haven't hit your
stride as a full 10 Buck bounty hunter
or whatever let's assume it's it's
roughly the same
um why is this better than what you're
currently doing and then the primary
answer I get back is like my work
workplace is fairly flexible so if I say
like hey I need to go run to a doctor's
appointment or I need to go you know go
on a walk with my kid or something like
that like they're like sure go for it
but like I I have to check in you know
and and and like
like you said you know making that sort
of small Flex things official as part of
the company I think that would be huge
and I think that would allow them to
retain Talent yeah you know in these
sort of situations because my friends
are like yeah you know what for me if I
want to just stand up and go get in my
hot tub or like you know go on a walk or
like you know something like that yeah I
don't want to have to tell someone about
that or if I need to go you know drop my
lawnmower off at Home Depot and get
fixed you know like very specific
situation here yeah yeah
um you know then you know I don't want
to have to check in with somebody to do
it I just want to do it you know yeah
and um I totally I totally feel that so
you know making that more official
making that more you know as part of the
company culture would be huge to retain
talent I think awesome awesome cool all
right well that was a little bit of a
more of a tangent than I thought it was
going to be better oh sorry
because it was chock full of awesome
information
um I did want to Circle back to like um
the asset Discovery stuff that you're
talking yeah yeah like obviously that's
like a huge part of the stuff that like
you've done yeah both from your history
the blog Hunters methodology like all
that kind of stuff
how much does your personal like hunting
and personal strategy shift away from
the stuff that you've published and
talked about is it basically just
one-to-one with bug Hunters methodology
you basically just like throw your
public word list on
fairix Buster and go forward or however
sometimes I do
um I mean it really depends on
on the Target right like so like some of
the Recon methodology is totally
invalidated if there's just one host in
the bug mounting right like uh so you
know it depends on what programs I'm
invited to I do prefer the larger recony
like uh friendly
um things because I have a couple
methods that are not published in my
Decks that still find me like really
good stuff and
um and all the public stuff still finds
me stuff too so
um yeah I mean I would say I'm a heavy
Recon based Hunter which I know is not
popular these days but that's okay
um I just really find old [__] that
people leave on the internet like that's
my skill I don't know why like um and
I'm not telling everybody else they have
to that needs to be their skill set and
I still hack apps and like all that
stuff like that but
um yeah I mean like uh I mean my when I
sit down to a program right like let's
say you know this week is the um is the
hacker one
um you know like uh World Cup right and
um I'm I'm on a team with Justin and uh
are Joel are you playing are you in the
other team no I'm on that one no okay
we're all on the same channel okay I was
on vacation when you guys started so I'm
like trying to like do stuff but it
wasn't really like I was still on
vacation so I'm gonna dive into this
movie yeah yeah anyway so yeah I mean
like when I looked at that list I was
like all right who's gonna have like a
lot of assets that I will be beneficial
for right and so like tonight I'm gonna
fire up all my automation
um on my VPS is and my new Axiom setup
and I'll start you know doing recon and
then you know like after I get done with
Recon I think people just make this jump
though when I give those talks
especially the Recon one they're like oh
recon's gonna find me bugs and that is
not that's where it falls apart right
like Recon doesn't really find you bugs
what Jason yeah like so so I use Recon
and I give all these esoteric methods of
Recon and I make a whole talk about
Recon to find more apps to hack like
that is the point find more apps because
the more apps you find the more of a
chance you have to succeed in hacking
right and so like that has always been
my thing right fine give myself more at
bats like if you're a baseball person or
whatever right like and so like yeah the
Recon for me like stops at subdomain
enumeration usually right every once in
a while a nuclei template will hit and
it's not a dupe that's like once every
six months or something like that right
like I use it to find the subs and then
I do the application hacking and then so
like if you want to break Recon into
kind of content Discovery and stuff like
that yeah I mean I have word lists my
all.txt I've been using
um uh six two does is new word list that
kind of combines all the all the word
lists the same before what is that
um it's called All For One I think
um
yeah it's a it's a word list did you say
the name was at six four six four Deads
he's the guy who writes Recon for the
win
um yeah
I will I will find it right now yes you
could yeah that that sounds real
interesting okay so he does one called
one list for all that's his project one
list for all yeah
um and so he's the he's the author of
um a Recon for the win but he basically
did what I did but updated it and um you
know what I did with the all list is
basically I went back through the 15
years I've been hacking and found all of
the tools that did content Discovery
basically uh you know file and directory
brute forcing and I just combined them
into one word list and yeah there was a
lot of trash in there but it was full
coverage of everything everybody had
done research on for that topic of
content Discovery so he did the same
thing
um and it's a huge list but I mean like
uh I I find stuff with it all the time
because it's agnostic to technology
um and it includes a lot of Legacy stuff
and I'm not I'm not this is not a burn
at anybody who's a younger tester but
you weren't around for if if you're
testing a legacy or organization right
um and so you know in the that's why
people are like oh why you know like why
does this hit why does not hit anything
for me well if you're using against like
a cloud-first organization none of that
[__] in there is gonna work right you
need it you need a better word list and
uh you know that's targeted towards that
technology but if you're targeting an
older company like my wordless kills
against Yahoo because they still have a
lot of Legacy Tech
um you know or like a a Walmart or
something like that like that that word
list has killed against Walmart even
though that's the they suck sometimes
yeah that's the thing yeah
[Laughter]
you know that's why I really like you
pointed out something really really
important there that I just wanted to
re-highlight which was like you if
you're if you're throwing you know this
these lists at like you know an S3
bucket you know yeah
um and so like you definitely got to
keep an eye out on that and make sure
you're not just wasting your your CPU
Cycles yeah exactly that's one of the
reasons I love asset notes word list
that they put out as well yeah just like
they're greatly phenomenal
um yeah and the UI is pretty too oh yeah
that's great yeah
so I mean they're the leaders in content
Discovery lists right now
um I mean before them they we had s me
and Digger and get Digger which was by
um some other consultancies but they are
the leader now and uh Long Live shubs
who is probably one of the smartest
smartest human beings and most
compassionate men I've ever met in my
life it's crazy man he's he's phenomenal
yeah I've had some legit mental health
struggles in the last couple years and
I've I've messaged shubs just feeling
like a freaking Noob and he has talked
me down a couple times and just been
like yo we're all like that and I'm so
good for that man he's he's an amazing
person that's that's what I'll say so
yeah he's an amazing guy he's been
through like so many different things
personally yeah he's a lot of amazing
insights on
yeah yeah just make sure you you Explore
More Than The Tech with him because he's
got so many layers right yeah yeah
so so it sounds like a lot of the time
you end up using just sort of all.txt
dude just literally like content
Discovery find interesting targets and
then down there it's all like
yeah yeah I mean I mean yeah I mean if
if I could describe the rest of it right
like um okay so I'm in I'm in burp
everything is for me right uh I'm not
one of the kind of guys who uses like
devtools um I find it too cluttered so I
mostly pipe everything through burp
um and then I'm just using the site like
a normal user if there's multiple roles
executing all the functions I can making
sure I hit the Deep areas of like uh
once a user logs in their configurations
or settings panels any API Integrations
and I talked about this in my newest bug
Hunters methodology I got way more into
the app hacking
um stuff and so I look at those and then
I think about an application as it's as
inputs which I've kind of been trained
as for many many years right and so
there are heat areas and application
anywhere that handles a URL or path you
know has the potential for certain
classes of bugs any place that handles a
reflected piece of text has you know how
has possibilities for certain types of
bugs and so what I'll usually do is I'll
look at the site tree or I'll use verbs
Dynamic analysis in Pro to look at all
of the dynamic parameters and I'll see
what's there and what got passed to them
and then I'll start fiddling with them
and I have a checklist to make sure that
I'm looking for all bug classes that
relate to the types of inputs so file
uploads and then I'll key in on things
like Json and XML response types because
those are usually associated web
services sometimes and then I'll move
into web hacking mode our web service
hacking mode or API mode and yeah and so
I mean that's pretty much the regular
type of appsec bug Hunter testing
workflow I think I just have you know 15
years of knowledge on uh you know which
I did that project of what parameters
are most likely vulnerable to which
things and so that that is one of my
superpowers like I can look yeah Hans
yeah which is imported to like several
different tools now but that has really
helped me in my testing over the years
so nice yeah I'm gonna pull up hunch
really quickly and I'm gonna put that in
my notes and then I've got here it is
I've got a question for you yeah um so
well first of all I just wanted to go
back and highlight
um you know what you said before
um you know the the dynamic analysis
piece that you that you reflected on
um in you know inside of burp I I want
to know how you how you did that
um and then also I for for the people
listening just kind of talking about
methodology you said you know there are
types of bug classes that appear when
you know URLs are being handled they're
content is being reflected this is the
sort of thing that you just kind of gave
me sixth sense for when you're an
experienced tester yeah
um and and so like I I just wanted to go
back and highlight those two things
because like
and and I I think you know people ask me
this all the time do you have like a
checklist that you kind of go through
and stuff like that and for a long time
the Bounty Hunter's methodology or the
bug Hunters methodology was that for me
and you know you've got some other stuff
out there with checklists and I think
that's great but as I've evolved as a
hacker and maybe this is different and I
know some people that do checklists and
do it very well but for me it becomes
more stuff like that like like this okay
there is a URL being parsed here there's
a variety of weird things that can
happen in the URLs being parsed there's
a variety of things that can happen when
a regex is being used there's a variety
of weird things that can be happening
when there's reflected content and those
sort of like sort of risk areas if you
guys can focus on on those sort of
things and gain you know a sense for
like when pitfalls happen as at a
general level yeah I think I think
that's going to really help you know
people level up as a as hackers because
that's what gets you off the checklist
and more thinking like as an attacker
methodology our attacker mentality going
into the application looking at it
feeling it you know I always talk about
feeling it you know getting intimate
with the application understanding all
the different pieces the way data flows
through it and where the sketchy things
happen and so here's the level up from
that that you know people eventually
grow into but uh and I saw you do it the
other day someone put something in our
hack uh in our hack channel for the
competition yeah and you're like well
they're using this language so they're
probably using this parser or this
library right and so like people always
talk about understand the technology
right and so the the maturation of a
tester is okay I understand that this
happening in the URL can be indicative
of these bugs and then the next level is
like oh because they're using this
coding language or they're hosting it
here or I've done some research on the
company or whatever I know that they're
using this stack and this is the thing
that's probably handling that URL and
here now I'm gonna go Google hey what
have the bugs been in the past is there
a way I can bypass this thing has there
been pre-existing research you know
that'll help me in my exploitation of
this type of bug you know whether it's a
URL parser or a file upload parser you
know or whatever that's like the next
step is like being a technology
specialist and being able to do that in
a short time too because like you you
know you only have so long to hack an
app if you're in a pen test or a bug
Bounty right so yeah yeah absolutely so
the dynamic analysis piece
um you know you said you were using burp
to figure out that um I I I'm not you
know a burp super pro
um what what are you using for that uh
so let me see here let me pull up real
quick
um I know there's like reflected
parameters so reflective parameters is a
oh it's not an extension it's base it's
in the base uh policies now so
um so really
I don't ever think honestly and and I'll
I'll just be totally honest about this
right I don't ever think I'm gonna do
probably a better job than Burke's
Dynamic Scanner with cross-site
scripting so I just have one I have one
policy in burp that checks for
cross-site scripting across the whole
site and I only run it on Dynamic
parameters which I get by I will tell
you right now right clicking on the
targets yeah
um and you go uh hold on uh
yeah I wanna I wanna poke around at it
and see because there's like analyze
Target which I don't use very often yes
that's it it's analog Target yeah it's
analystick so you right click on a host
and you choose uh engagement tools okay
analyze Target and then you go to
Dynamic URLs and that's everything that
is past data
um against a site and so that really
trims down like all of the you know
static content and everything and that's
that's kind of where I focus after I've
done a full walkthrough of the app now
it doesn't always work right like single
page applications are not gonna you know
they're not gonna like work the same way
and
um you know yeah but but for in general
most sites who who pass data you know
via post requests will you know uh we'll
be there and even get requests too where
it sees like uh larger payloads
um or you know larger URLs or parameters
in the URL or things that things are
rest parameters it will it will count as
Dynamic and so you look at Dynamic URLs
and then you can check each Dynamic URL
for what params it sends and you just
start analyzing like that basically
basically dude that's that's old man I I
I always find new cool pieces of burp
when I talk to you know amazing testers
that I that I respect and yeah it's it's
so great to to get everyone's way that
they use this tool yeah and uh yeah and
kaido is going to be making you know its
own there's going to be those same
things in kaido as well there's a couple
features that kaido has already that I
just I love that are that are not in
bird particularly I'll call this one out
I hate how in burp when you intercept
you have to click forward forward
forward until you find the request
you're looking for yeah in kaido it cues
them all up okay and then you can just
like you can jump when you want and oh
that's cool that's very cool oh my gosh
it's just a game changer yeah so a lot
of the times I end up just you know
right clicking say always accept from
this host because it's always like add
an analytics Frameworks loading and like
all kinds of like apis that I'm not
testing but I end up having to do that
process like 10 times and I'm like oh my
God
the one part I will say is you can can
do some adjustments on the on the
interception side so where it says like
intercept these requests either from the
client like the request or the responses
you could say it has to meet certain
criteria so I'll have to say like it has
to be within my defined scope questions
yeah and maybe I'll add like an extra
like condition like it needs to match
this path or right should be on this
host or something so it'll only like
yeah I might have to click forward a
couple times but it'll be less than it
would be yeah like with all the tracking
pixels and everything the thing is less
annoying is is that like I've known
about that trick for a while and I use
it I literally am looking at it checked
right now
um the the uh is in Target scope
intercept rule yeah but the thing is I
do a lot of
um right lately I've been doing a lot of
client-side stuff um and uh sometimes
I'll be you know poking at how they
enter they interact with like you know
third-party libraries and what kind of
stuff they're loading in and what kind
of JavaScript they're they're trusting
you know to run on their page
um and so sometimes I do want to
intercept things that are outside of my
scope at a time like uncheck it and then
I check it and then uncheck it and I
check it and you know burp did a good
job of I think putting that settings
panel in a different
um window now uh the latest version of
burp um so you can kind of keep it up
and you know on one of your monitors or
something like that if you want to but
um yeah still still a pain point for me
I must say
so the the other part of the question I
think was like is like fuzzing I think
you were trying to get at and like you
know so I have I have sec lists I have a
couple other fuzzing projects like the
awesome fuzzing project on GitHub but
web buzzing is part of my workflow
um so it's not just parameter analysis
and I have like this thing that I
remember in my head it's like
um it's uh sensitive secrets were leaked
recently and it's an acronym for how I
basically think about
um when I fuzz with random data either
big payload small payloads you know
different type of attack payloads as a
you know either a arrest request or a
parameter request parameter value
request I look at the status code the
size the words line and the return time
basically and so in each of those I'm
looking for different things one more
time it's sensitive secrets were leaked
recently so status code write it down
sensitive Secrets
recently status code status code size
words
where lines return time lines okay
and so so with status code obviously
you're looking you want to focus in on
the app anytime you get a non
non-standard status code right and so
you learn these as you test right you
said it yourself like this is years of
testing condensed into like an acronym
right but but basically status code you
know any errors I want to over index on
to see how I cause that error with my
fuzzing payloads and what payload was it
um with my size I want to see you know
you'll get non-standard return sizes
right so you want to sort the column
invert by return or return size of the
of the binary payload of the return of
the HTTP request lines also can be
indicative if new content was loaded on
the page while you were testing that
maybe you you got access to especially
error reports that leak credentials or
things like that like error messages
that just dump on the screen and stuff
return time shows you know the
indicativeness of like a parser or
something like that
um you know taking too much time to
parse a file or a fuzzing payload you
gave it and then that's something you
want to test for like you know dos or
application dos or something like that
or you know um you know a myriad of
other bugs but yeah that's kind of how I
look at at all responses and analyze
them when I'm doing like actual fuzzing
so dude it's kind of crazy man like I I
um
I think one of the mistakes that I made
earlier in my in my career was I was
working with a lot of people that were
older than me and that were my senior in
organizations and I found them not
Technical and so I really just kind of
dissed that you know I was like you know
what you know I'm I am I'm the
generation that you know understood you
know that I grew up with computers and
stuff like that and then I meet like a
couple edge cases like you and fronds
and people like that that are just like
you know a little bit above me but also
like you know in age-wise but it just
like have been doing the same thing for
years and years and years and then I
just get like Blown Away by like oh yeah
I've got this acronym that I just pulled
off at the top of my head about how I
you know
what the heck like yeah dude it's it's
such a pleasure to to get you on here
and talking about this stuff and and see
you know what it can look like you know
as experienced compounds experience plus
interest in in bug Downey hacking
compound over time
um man this is awesome and you can
combine that with with
um James kettle's backslash powered
scanner so uh that will that will do
fuzz testing of all the special
characters and then backslash Escape
them and so you use that acronym
sensitive Secrets where we were leaked
recently with that to kind of get custom
fuzz cases for web applications that's
that's awesome dude yeah I that's one of
the areas that I think I need to
progress in as a hacker is fuzzing and
and uh you know
I I'm finding this right now where at
the Target that I'm looking at for the
World Cup I'm trying to find I've got a
very specific narrow scope that I've
locked myself down to and I say I've got
to find every single functionality that
this website has yes
um and for that you've got fuss because
you know you're you know you can pull
GAO you can pull yeah you know anything
and and like you're still not going to
find the stuff that you know the very
large percentage of stuff that somehow
doesn't get you know put in archive or
like virus total or whatever it pulls
from
um and so yeah fuzzing is definitely an
area that I would like to I would like
to level up on yep
um all right Joel we are at one hour 20
minutes I could talk to Jason forever I
mean I got time if you guys want to do
it I mean I think I think we may
actually make this like a very long
episode uh because I still got a couple
other things I want to hear about your
reports for sure yeah Joel do you have
anything you want to hit before we get
to the reports nah not nothing important
I feel like we've done a really good job
of sort of covering like most of the
questions that we come up with because
it's a pretty natural flow so cool all
right so Jason yeah this is this is um
you know this is something we want to
try to hit with for people that come
onto the podcast
um one of the big things we do here is
kind of talk about reports and like get
in the weeds of technical
vulnerabilities which you just did a
great job of doing you've been doing a
great job of doing both on the soft
skill size and and on the technical side
which is phenomenal
um but yeah I hit you up in advance you
know some reports so let's uh let's well
first actually let me ask this do you
have a particular favorite bug type that
you've got or like like you know some
bug type where you're just like oh I
love finding this like did anything that
does that for you yeah I mean I really
like authorization bypass
um a lot
um it's my it's like one of my favorites
uh just to I don't know if it's the
smirkiness of just having bypass logins
you know like I don't know like what
that is like yeah um which usually comes
through like you know different methods
of content discovery which you know a
lot of people are like Ah that's not
hacking but I mean I sure as hell get
access to accounts so you know yeah so
that's great man so yeah so
authorization authorization bypass yeah
or authentication bypass
um you know what is your in just you
know uh we don't have to get get too
much into the weeds but if you could
just give us a little bit of a brief
methodology for for finding nodes that
you kind of want to share and uh yeah
yeah yeah so
um I mean so identifying how
applications uh I talked about this in
my last talk about how applications
reference users in an application is
really important right whether it's a
uuid or it's completely based on the
session token and every request that you
pass but like invariably applications
will you know add more functionality
onto the app which you know sometimes
they'll even create edge cases where
they introduce a you know uuid or
something like that and is it as simple
as an email address that's representing
a user or is it you know like a
randomized token or how random is the
token and so for authorization
authentication I will first I want to
identify like what is it that's making
me me right and then I want to identify
if there's multiple user levels in the
account that
um that you know have more power than me
to do cool stuff that I can't do right
so many applications have this nowadays
and so there's plenty of videos out
there now but I mean until very recently
there wasn't and you know using
authorize or auth Matrix are two tools
inside of burp that I used to do
manually and I still honestly probably
do more manually than I use the plugins
but I just create I create an Excel
table which I know is so ghetto but I
create an Excel table of everything I
can do and every one of those Dynamic
functions in one account
and that I can do and then I log out and
then I create another account or I just
create another browser instance and I
try to access the other users session uh
or you know basically areas
um I I try to substitute numerical IDs
if I've referenced this in Miracle uuid
I try to do all kinds of trickery and I
spend about you know two hours probably
doing that stuff between accounts and
then if I can get access to an
administrator account I try to make sure
that both an unlocked user and a regular
user can't access the administrative
function via just post requests and you
know whatever else API calls or whatever
and so really on the website and kind of
the configuration panels and most app
functions it's very it's getting better
these days that these bugs don't exist
as much as they used to they used to be
all over the place I used to find all
the time but now they've shifted to the
API world where there's multiple user
levels in the API world and now it's
just kind of shifted over the API and
API developers are a new breed of you
know younger developers who you know
unless they have a framework that's
strictly telling them how to segregate
user roles they don't and it's and you
get wrecked by you know like uh by these
types of bugs against apis
um so the other one I really like though
is
um
uh and and this one um I was really
validated when I went to go actually see
Mark Litchfield doesn't hardly ever talk
about his methodology except for when he
used to have his sight
um yeah but I went to a talk that he did
at um Tinder
um where I talked next or after him and
I was really validated because his old
talk was his approach to finding
authorization bypass against
um big sites man what I wouldn't give to
have seen that it was it was amazing
because I was like yes I do this too
this is awesome
um and so one of the stories I had was
basically
um this this company that had a bug
Bounty scope
um and uh what they needed was a CRM for
their business
um to to integrate with their platform
and so what they did is I found out via
press releases they bought another
company they acquired a CRM company a
small one but an up-and-coming small CRM
company
um and they purchase it for use uh
on them and so the website was still up
for the CRM software for the old company
to run a demo and so like you know I had
found the CRM instance that the new
company had stood up and uh and
basically
um you know they had branded it like
they wanted to Brand it changed its name
but it was still the same software and
all I had access to was a login portal
which I had no credentials to
um and so what I you know what I did and
you know you should add this to your
methodology I think it happened with my
talks is is I found the core software
and you can do this if it's open source
code but you can also do it if it's not
open source code but they still have a
demo portal available for the old site
and so I went to the old developers
website I logged into their demo portal
which they gave away for free
um to you know test the CRM and I just
mapped it in burp and then I exported
all those URLs to a file and just
replace the domain
for uh for the new company
without any authentication and I started
replaying the requests and the URLs and
the endpoints against the new thing and
I found a couple paths where they had
forgot to lock down uh permissions
um one of them
um was this function in this app in the
CRM that managed
um text message or SMS based message uh
to their users
um and so uh basically I had access to
this control panel that had their API
key for this text message service and I
could send text messages to over I think
there was four million clients already
in the CRM yeah
um so I had that API key and I could do
that by just taking the API key and then
using it directly with the service
through like a you know like a curl
request
um and then so I kept looking and I
found some other places where it wasn't
locked down and I'm trying to remember
uh so I submitted that as a bug that was
a big one
um and then I found I found found a
Verbatim API that they had set up and I
had some predefined paths from the eight
for the API which was a user access it
was an API call to basically deliver
your profile settings
but you know like many apis do they'll
give you back everything but it had a
user variable in the in the URL it was
like it was a numeric variable and they
just hadn't made it unique at all it was
like it was like six characters or
something like that and so I brute force
that path and I had the one from the old
website so I knew it was six characters
and so I brute force that path to seven
characters I think in burp and I hit
eventually I hit one of the admins of
the applications uh profile setting API
endpoint and that returned his uh his
password a Verbatim password
and so then I logged in I logged into
the application on their side and I had
access to every this CRM was crazy like
the amount of information it had like
was nuts this company is huge they're
worldwide like worldwide brand and so I
mean and then I just wrote up the most
amazing finding you can think of them
with this access I can basically do
anything I was like I'll push text
messages and JavaScript into your app to
take over all their users phones like
yeah I made a little proof of I was like
so this customer is notorious for like
prove the impact and I was like I am
writing a report that absolutely shows
what I could do as a malicious person
here just so you know there is impact
yeah yes exactly yeah there is not any
lack of impact yeah exactly so the trick
there is is like basically you know when
you're testing and you're testing
against a uh cots I call it common
off-the-shelf software whether it's open
source or it's had a demo at some point
dump install it yourself yeah awesome
acronyms oh thanks yeah yeah uh yeah
Katz is actually an industry one so okay
is it yeah software yeah so you know
whether you purchase it or whether it's
open source or whether it was closed
sourced as a SAS try to get access to
the software install it yourself off
dump all of the endpoints and parameters
that you can from your install or from
the live running demo or whatever and
then replay those against the site and I
have hit that so many times against uh
bug bounties for authorization issues
dude it's crazy like it's so funny you
mentioned this because we're we're all
in this you know hacker One World Cup
thing yeah and I've got a guy right now
that I'm working with on our team that
uh he's like oh this host is kind of
interesting right and I look at it and I
literally did that exact same thing like
I went to the the website there's a demo
portal you could log in with with
default credentials you know you get in
there you figure out how the app is
structured you pull all the routes you
try to hit those routes on the actual
website yeah and dude that's such a gold
technique yeah it's landed me so many
bugs and then you know what we did is
there's also you know you can buy the
software for pretty cheap yeah so we
just you know paid the money you know
got the software and and pull it down
and just start reading through getting
access to source code and when you've
got access to source code the game gets
so much easier oh yeah for sure start
you know even if you're just grabbing
off of keywords or anything like that
you know it's it's a big big difference
so so big second to that yeah tip that's
a great one Jason so the the follow-up
on that is that um so this is one not a
lot of people know and I'll let it go on
the podcast so hell yeah uh is that many
of those paid software that you don't
want to pay for that are that are made
by big companies like maybe that you
know rhyme with Oracle or something like
that I don't know like
um the most boring company out there
yeah uh many developers develop their
environments in Docker and then they
upload a Docker file of the installed
software to Docker Hub or another
service like Docker Hub and you can
scroll down
okay all the time okay sorry I'm
releasing your guys's Secrets here but
uh shut up Jason
so you download that Docker Hub and you
host it yourself and now you have access
to source code review which gives you a
heads up against many many many many
things so oh yeah yeah and I talked
about this at my my Defcon talk this
past year as well it's like you know I
it was it was um Sam herb that I was
working on a program with and he did
this exact same same thing went down
pulled the docker down yeah you know you
didn't even have to pay for the software
because the dockerized version you know
it requires you to put in a license key
yeah or whatever but you can just pop in
there and grab all the you know source
code and stuff like that so that's a big
that's a big one
um a big win for sure that that people
should be on the look out for yep uh so
I I had one other one that was more just
fun than really technical but um I
pulled it because a lot of mine I like a
lot of my best hacks I post on Twitter
as threads yeah
um
and I I obviously obfuscate on the names
and everything like that but I think
they're fun to read for people and so
some of my good ones I've already had I
wanted to bring you guys that weren't on
the web yet that eventually I will turn
into threads but they're not there yet
so this one
um was a major auto manufacturer that's
what I will say Okay
um and uh it wasn't in the last big
batch of Sam's research with um with the
homsack and Zion and everybody but um
but uh it was in kind of a previous
generation of of car hacking
um and so this one was actually Recon
based so I had started uh basically
looking at the site and one of the
things I like to do is I call it
um what the hell do I call I put it one
of my talks but it's like it's like uh
recursive Recon or whatever basically
you load up your site in burp and you
set up a keyword in your site uh in your
scope settings that says to allow scope
with the keyword in it of the company so
not a domain so not like you know uh
you know not uh tesla.com but just the
word Tesla right you want to see
everything how I do my my scope setup
okay cool yeah yeah exactly like yeah
company word or yep keep phrase exactly
four domains yep so that's what I do and
then I recursively spider all those
sites so I'll spider everything that
comes up in me browsing the site and
then I'll select everything and spider
it again and then I'll just do it until
there's no more sites basically that are
cross-linked between everything and so
it gives me a pretty good feel of
everything that has that keyword in it
and so I end up getting all of these
weird top level or you know domains not
sub domains but domains that I have
never seen before that have the keyword
in them and I'm like oh that's pretty
cool so I was doing this for a big auto
manufacturer and I found this domain
that was like random four letter words
I'm sure they're abbreviation for
something and then the keyword and I'm
like that domain seems interesting so I
go looking at that domain and it's
basically just a blank white page right
and like like okay that's weird like
whatever so I started doing content
discovery on this blank white page right
which is kind of what I do because
there's nothing else to do there right
like there's no content right so it's
like whatever so I start doing content
Discovery and I start getting hits back
for
um for pass for Jenkins and
um and for some other you know CI CD
tools and I'm like oh okay cool so I
start loading up my browser and so the
story behind this is It's not that fancy
right I did content Discovery I
basically walked into an unsecured
Jenkins install
um um I basically walked into what else
they had sonotype Nexus running up there
um it was all on good yeah all source
code yeah all source code for the
organization like all of their
infotainment source code uh it was nuts
but that's awesome uh the story is that
I found out from a person that works
there after I submitted the bug Bounty
thing and she's like he's like I gotta
tell you the story about this thing and
I'm like okay and he's like
we have been
telling our developer staff that they
can't move to Modern CI CD tools for
longest time because we're in waterfall
and like we're an old car company and
like we're just not going to you know
move yet we are eventually but we're not
yet the development team by themselves
purchased a domain and started using the
CI CD tools that they wanted without
telling the organization why so the org
had no idea this whole domain was public
to the internet and it had all of the
the source code in it and like and they
had just gone Rogue basically because
the org wouldn't let them getting fired
yeah right and so you know like I I mean
I had again I wrote up like a pretty
exhaust defining I had so many
hard-coded credentials in the source I
had I had like access to everything I
could show this I could shell the domain
or the server that Jenkins was on
because it had the script console thing
where you can run jobs and that's a
common red team or tactic and yeah
um but yeah I mean there's like four
different source code tools on there uh
I think it was sonotype Texas Jenkins
team Forge was on there and some other
stuff too and uh yeah but I just thought
it was super funny that like the dev
team had just gone Rogue and started
using all these tools security team's
nightmare yeah I know it's absolutely
security team's nightmare yeah but I
thought that was a funny one it's crazy
you know did we see that
at the time too yeah like yeah that
absolutely does happen and yeah and it's
a different world you know in the
security world so yeah sometimes when
you're dealing with the bureaucracy you
know who knows someone might just go
around it yeah the uh the other one
that's similar to that is is I was on a
bounty and I found a red team
infrastructure for their Go Fish
instance and so I found it on the
internet and I was doing recon and I'm
like what is this domain that looks kind
of like the other domains but is coming
up and they had what did they they had
cross-linked it somewhere that I had hit
on it and it showed up and burp and like
I was like weird and then I go to it and
it's like a Go Fish install and default
like I had a pretty default credential
like admin admin or something like that
and I log into their Go Fish instance
and I'm like is this a finding like if I
found your red teams like Go Fish
instance holy crap it was it was super
funny and my friend works on that red
team and he's like bro you just burnt
our domain
I
you know
well I won't share too much details but
you know I I have been convicted in the
past of like uh you know I'm writing
this code right now this is [__] code
you know
like I know it but I've got to write it
anyway but I know it so like that's the
difference
that's the difference between me and the
devs is I know I'm making a double steak
Yeah and uh I think the last one was one
that I did do a thread on but it was um
the password manager that we hacked so
um so this was back in my early early
pen test days and there were multiple
players in the password kind of LastPass
um there was several uh back then that
were trying to win the space and so uh
basically
um we were on this call and at that time
it was my salesperson Deanna who is the
nicest person in the world
um she she set up this call with this
company they contacted us actually and
they were abusive to her on the phone
like basically like just jerks they're
like you know like I don't even know why
we're talking to your company we
wouldn't have to do this unless we were
compliance we're one of the best Dev
teams in the world like
um your team's not going to find
anything like they gave her a hassle
about like pricing and communication you
know Cadence and she was awesome she was
like the coolest person at the company
honestly dang um and so she came to us
the engineering team of you know you
normally this the project is only
supposed to be applied to one of us for
a web piece right and she's like she's
like can you guys wreck this company and
I was and we were like exactly what I
was hoping yeah and we were like we were
like yes Deanna we will do that for you
and so it was yeah yeah
and and you know maybe it was a tactic
of theirs to try to piss off us to get
better testing but they got good testing
so
um so I spent a I had spent a week
um doing recon and I was getting like
not Recon but like um you know basically
application profiling and I hadn't
really found too much yet
um they managed their password manager
via bookmarklet and um or an extension
and it was pretty much same they had a
public-facing website
um you know with standard functionality
uh that would that would log you into
like your Vault that would pull things
from you know that would interact with
the extension and um so like this is
very early on in my web testing so I did
content Discovery with back then it was
um durbuster
um and so I had found a whole bunch of
paths that were giving me 403s and other
error codes that were not standard one
of them was like Gmail PHP one of them
was uh one of them was phpmyadmin but
they were locked down right I couldn't
get to them
um and uh keywords that are really
taking me back yeah yeah yeah my admin
right it's all this one's old yeah here
we go yeah actually PHP my admin was not
locked down it just was a login screen
though and I didn't have credentials for
it and so
um what what we ended up doing is the
the fuzzing methodology that I've been
doing for years right is is I just
started fuzzing every Dynamic parameter
and at one point I hit uh I hit a
minifier
um parameter and it started giving weird
error messages and I found that out
through the the word count basically
um and so I was like this is weird so I
went to my buddy Paul who was much
smarter than me at the time in web
testing and I was like hey we might want
to look at this and also we're getting
at the end of our testing window and you
know like let's let's just dive into
this and he's like okay
so we're all doing different parts and
we had all discovered like some paths
but nothing really critical and so by
fuzzing this Minify function
um we were noticing that it was giving
us error codes that said like like
incorrect pathing or something like that
and we were like that's weird it's
referencing pathing maybe we can pop an
lfi here
um and but we couldn't get it so we
spent three days playing with this error
code and
um and then you know we did the the
standard investigation okay what are
they coding the front end and it was
like code igniter basically and we were
like okay so like let's look through the
codeigniter documentation and we sound
this the small reference in the code
igniter documentation I think it was
that sometimes you can change the dots
in a path reference to underscores to
work better with the web basically for
some reason and so we replaced the dots
with underscores in our lfi path and
we're able to Echo out files from the
web server yep so then so then we you
know we go through every page that we
had found Echo at the source code for
all the pages
um the web root was pretty standard now
yeah yeah yeah so
um and then eventually we go to that the
content Discovery we had done and we
start echoing those pages that we had
found through the content so gmail.php
echoed out an integration script for the
the main developer of the site that had
his personal Gmail credentials in the in
the integration script and so then we
log into his personal Gmail of which he
has source code in his um in his uh his
Google drive basically yep and his
Google Drive and so we're like messing
around in there
um and then uh we were able to
uh we were able to eventually get a
credential from his Google Drive that
logged us into phpi my admin uh and then
uh we got into phpmyadmin we added our
own super user accounts injecting a hash
directly into the database through
phpmyadmin
um and then uh what else did we do dude
I love this so much yeah it was just
like yeah this is like what red team
I mean we did some other stuff too like
eventually we back door to the plug-in a
version of the plugin not the production
live one but we said here's what we
could have done we could have backed the
plug-in and or the extension and pulled
everybody's passwords as they were
making them uh we found Co we found
cross-site scripting once we had access
to Circuit oh that's what we did so once
we had the lfi not only did we pull down
the pages we knew existed for the
website but we went through we installed
like I said this is part of the
methodology we installed codeigniter a
codeigniter bass install on one of our
servers and then took out all the paths
and files that we saw from that as a
list and then ran it through the lfi and
through that we got API keys that they
had hard-coded in source code and like
uh we had so much information and it was
it was great we had completely owned
them by the end and we went on this call
on the on the like kickoff call and they
were like so confident that we weren't
going to find anything and so we start
going through the report how we had just
wrecked them and they were like they
were just dogs yeah yeah we have
screenshots together yeah we have
screenshots of the dude's personal email
people are g-chatting him and we're just
like we're like yeah this is us like in
your your email and
um yeah so that was that was one of the
more satisfying ones of my career and it
took a village it took all four of us
you know at the end but uh that is that
is it was so fun you really defended
your your sales person there yeah
awesome yeah that's that's awesome to
hear and and I don't know I when I was
in when I was in Consulting I definitely
liked working with the people that were
more alike all right let's like work
together on this yeah exactly value out
of this yeah but there is definitely
those moments where the people are like
yeah you know if you find anything let
us know yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah all
right yeah yeah let's go like a hacker
challenge you're like let's go all right
yeah that's great man yeah we are at
Joel we're at an hour 45 minutes oh I'm
sorry I'm so sorry guys no Jason no this
is awesome yeah it's phenomenal content
wouldn't shade it for the world
um let's wrap it up though Jason is
there any you already shouted out
butobot um you know quite extensively
yes product there but anything else you
want us to you know you want to shout
out here at the end uh no I just I'm
super glad you guys are doing this
podcast I think that we need more uh
like bug Bounty type stuff you know
I don't know I think bug bounty hunters
are no different than any other security
testers right so I actually don't think
of this as a bug value podcast I think
of you guys as like an appsec or a
testing podcast right and so we just
need more of it out there people talking
about stuff especially people who are
familiar with new school developments
and cloud and and stuff like that so I'm
just really happy that I got a chance to
come on talk to you guys and really
appreciate it and if you're out there
and you're hacking just keep hacking you
know keep at it
for sure all right awesome awesome yeah
you can find them JJ haddocks on Twitter
yeah yeah Jay had most places yeah yeah
dude this was an awesome conversation
thanks so much no no problem thanks guys
awesome awesome the pod sweet see ya
cool